{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q2": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "As we said before, PDAs have 2 different types of language acceptance. In this module we will cver the second type of acceptance.",
        "question": "What was the first one?",
        "answer": "Final State acceptance",
        "choices": ["Final State acceptance", "Empty Stack acceptance"]
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definition:}$ Let NPDA $M = (Q, \\Sigma, \\Gamma, \\delta, q_0, z, \\emptyset)$ accepts $L(M)$ by empty stack, $L(M) = \\{w \\in \\Sigma^* | (q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$",
        "question": "Look carefully at the definition of $M$. What is missing?",
        "answer": "Set of final states",
        "choices": ["Start state", "Set of final states", "Set of alphabets", "Set of stack symbols", "Set of states", "Stack start symbol"]
      },
      "q4": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definition:}$ Let NPDA $M = (Q, \\Sigma, \\Gamma, \\delta, q_0, z, \\emptyset)$ accepts $L(M)$ by empty stack, $L(M) = \\{w \\in \\Sigma^* | (q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$",
        "question": "By reading $(q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$. What does it mean that $q_0$ changed to $p$?",
        "answer": "The machine moved from start stat to another state $q$",
        "choices": ["The machine moved from start stat to another state $q$", "The string is consumed by machine", "The stack content is changed based on the transitions"]
      },
      "q5": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definition:}$ Let NPDA $M = (Q, \\Sigma, \\Gamma, \\delta, q_0, z, \\emptyset)$ accepts $L(M)$ by empty stack, $L(M) = \\{w \\in \\Sigma^* | (q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$",
        "question": "By reading $(q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$. Is $p$ a final state?",
        "answer": "No, we do not have a final state in this type of acceptance",
        "choices": ["No, we do not have a final state in this type of acceptance", "Yes"]
      },
      "q6": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definition:}$ Let NPDA $M = (Q, \\Sigma, \\Gamma, \\delta, q_0, z, \\emptyset)$ accepts $L(M)$ by empty stack, $L(M) = \\{w \\in \\Sigma^* | (q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$",
        "question": "By reading $(q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$. What does it mean that $w$ changed to $\\lambda$?",
        "answer": "The string is consumed by machine",
        "choices": ["The machine moved from start stat to another state $q$", "The string is consumed by machine", "The stack content is changed based on the transitions"]
      },
      "q7": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definition:}$ Let NPDA $M = (Q, \\Sigma, \\Gamma, \\delta, q_0, z, \\emptyset)$ accepts $L(M)$ by empty stack, $L(M) = \\{w \\in \\Sigma^* | (q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$",
        "question": "By reading $(q_0, w, z) \\stackrel{*}{\\vdash} (p, \\lambda, \\lambda)\\}$. What does it mean that $z$ changed to $\\lambda$?",
        "answer": "The stack is empty",
        "choices": ["The machine moved from start stat to another state $q$", "The string is consumed by machine", "The stack is empty"]
      },
      "q8": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ Consider the following PDA",
        "question": "What is the language represented by the PDA?",
        "answer": "$L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$",
        "choices": ["$L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$", "$L = \\{a^nb^{n+m}c^m | n, m> 0\\}, \\Sigma=\\{a, b, c\\}$"]
      },
      "q9": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Is string $aabccc$ in the language?",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q10": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "What is the memory we need to trace the string",
        "answer": "Stack",
        "choices": ["Stack", "Queue"]
      },
      "q11": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_1$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q12": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Push $0$",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q13": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Stay at $q_1$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q14": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Push $0$",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q15": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_2$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q16": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Push $0$",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q17": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_3$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q18": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Pop the top",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q19": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Stay at $q_3$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q20": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Pop the top",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q21": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Stay at $q_3$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q22": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Pop the top",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q23": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_4$ and pop $Z$ from the stack",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$ and pop $Z$ from the stack", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q24": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabccc$",
        "question": "Will the string be accepted?",
        "answer": "Yes, the machine ended with empty stack",
        "choices": ["Yes, the machine ended with empty stack", "No, the machine end in a non-final state"]
      },
      "q25": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "What about the string $aabc$, will it be accepted?",
        "answer": "No, it is not in the language",
        "choices": ["No, it is not in the language", "Yes"]
      },
      "q26": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_1$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q27": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Push $0$",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q28": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Stay at $q_1$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q29": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Push $0$",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q30": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_2$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q31": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Push $0$",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q32": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the machine?",
        "answer": "Move to $q_3$",
        "choices": ["Move to $q_1$", "Move to $q_2$", "Move to $q_3$", "Move to $q_4$", "Stay at $q_1$", "Stay at $q_2$", "Stay at $q_3$"]
      },
      "q33": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Based on the top of the stack and the heighlighted input letter, what will happen to the Stack?",
        "answer": "Pop the top",
        "choices": ["Push $0$", "Pop the top", "Push $\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q34": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ $L = \\{a^nb^mc^{n+m} | n,m > 0\\}, \\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}, \\Gamma =\\{0, z\\}$<br/>Let us see the trace for the string $aabc$",
        "question": "Will the string be accepted?",
        "answer": "No, the machine is finished all steps and ended with non empty stack",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No, the machine is finished all steps and ended with non empty stack"]
      }
    }
  }
}